how to find the ideal protocol for one
patient. I tend just to listen to the
patient what their life looks like. It's
as simple as that. So, I know there's a
lot of stuff out there like uh when they
say gels don't work. Don't ever touch
them. No, no topical preparations.
They're all rubbish. That's sometimes
what the internet says. And I always
tell patients, just hear me out and then
I'll listen to you. So, I had one
patient who was a traveling salesman,
for example. They just wanted something
to put in their suitcase. no messing
about. That's it. And they're open to
anything. Well, gel's quite a good
option then. Especially if your symptoms
aren't like crushing your life, then
it's actually well, there's some logic
in trying it then. You might have mild
symptoms, the worst it could do is waste
a bit of your time and it's easy to
transport. And if you're traveling a lot
abroad, for example, the gel's easy to
take with you. Um, if for example,
you've got young children, they're
grabbing you all the time and things and
persontoperson transfer is a problem,
then probably stay away from the gels.
E, even some of the reps are saying
this. It's just not worth the risk of
persontoerson transfer. If you've got a
job where you're sweating, for example,
then maybe the gel isn't so good for
that. But if you've got clotting
disorder, uh, then the gels, they're
most gently absorbed. they don't they're
associated with less clot risk and
things like this, then I'd say that's a
no-brainer that you'd have to try that
first. Um, if you don't want to do
something every day, then injections are
good. Um, once a week injections, a lot
of patients do well on that. I do
recognize some don't. Some do get a mini
peak and trough. You can do daily if you
want, but then you're back to having to
administer something every day, which
may or may not be something you want to
do. Um, I found that kind of two or
three times a week injections for most
patients tends to serve them quite well.
And if it's um, and I know there's seven
days in the week, how do you divide that
by two or three? I just say Monday,
Thursday for twice a week in the
morning, Monday, Wednesday, Friday for
three times a week. Don't worry about
the Sunday. And and that pretty much
sorts most things out. If you get it
done in the morning, you can then get to
a lab. You've got many opportunities to
get your bloods done. uh where you can
get a trough sample for us to analyze
it. So I tend just to hear people out. I
explain everything from start to finish
how they all work. I answer any
questions you may have come across on
the internet in my consultations and
then I just talk with you about uh what
you think's best. Most of the time I
want the patient just to be happy. So as
long as they've not said anything that's
unsafe, I'll totally go with what
they've just said. And if you go into
your treatment happy, then to me that
says you're going to do the best. You're
happy with it. So you'll go into it more
relaxed. You won't be as apprehensive.
And I I think you'll do better.